uptimerobot.com 2019-12-25

# Privacy Policy | Uptime Robot

Uptime Robot (a service by Uptime Robot Service Provider Ltd.) operates several websites including [uptimerobot.com](https://uptimerobot.com/), [api.uptimerobot.com](http://api.uptimerobot.com/) and [blog.uptimerobot.com](https://blog.uptimerobot.com/). It is Uptime Robot's policy to respect your privacy regarding any information we may collect while operating our websites.

## What This Policy Covers

This Privacy Policy applies to information that we collect about you when you use:

  * Our website uptimerobot.com;
  * Our mobile applications (including the Uptime Robot mobile app for Android and iOS);

Throughout this Privacy Policy, we’ll refer to our website, mobile applications and other products and services collectively as “Services.”

Below we explain how we collect, use, and share information about you, along with the choices that you have with respect to that information.

## Information We Collect

We only collect information about you if we have a reason to do so–for example, to provide our Services, to communicate with you, or to make our Services better.

We collect information in two ways: if and when you provide information to us and automatically through operating our Services. Let’s go over the information that we collect.

#### _**Information You Provide to Us**_

It’s probably no surprise that we collect information that you provide to us. The amount and type of information depends on the context and how we use the information. Here are some examples:

  * **Basic Account Information:** We ask for basic information from you in order to set up your account. For example, we require individuals who sign up for an uptimerobot.com account to provide name-surname, email address , password and that’s it.
  * **Transaction and Billing Information:** If you buy something from us–a subscription to a uptimerobot.com plan, SMS messages, etc., for example–you will provide additional personal and payment information that is required to process the transaction and your payment, such as your name, credit card information, and contact information.
  * **Credentials:** Depending on the Services you use, you may provide us with credentials for your website (like SSH, FTP, and SFTP username and password).
  * **Communications With Us (Hi There!):** You may also provide us information when you respond to surveys or communicate with our team about a support question.

#### _**Information We Collect Automatically**_

We also collect some information automatically:

  * **Log Information:** Like most online service providers, we collect information that web browsers, mobile devices, and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, IP address, unique device identifiers, language preference, referring site, the date and time of access, operating system, and mobile network information. We collect log information when you use our Services–for example, when you create or make changes to your account.
  * **Usage Information:** We collect information about your usage of our Services. For example, we collect information about the pages you visit or site parts that you check the most. We use this information to, for example, provide our Services to you, as well as get insights on how people use our Services, so we can make our Services better.
  * **Location Information:** We may determine the approximate location of your device from your IP address. We collect and use this information to, for example, calculate how many people visit our Services from certain geographic regions.
  * **Information from Cookies & Other Technologies:** A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Pixel tags (also called web beacons) are small blocks of code placed on websites and emails. Uptime Robot uses cookies and other technologies like pixel tags to help us identify and track visitors, usage, and access preferences for our Services, as well as track and understand email campaign effectiveness.

And, we will only keep your personal information for as long as it is necessary for the purposes set out in this privacy policy, unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by law (such as tax, accounting or other legal requirements). 

## How And Why We Use Information

#### _**Purposes for Using Information**_

We use information about you as mentioned above and for the purposes listed below:

  * To provide our Services–for example, to set up and maintain your account or charge you for any of our paid Services;
  * To further develop and improve our Services–for example by adding new features that we think our users will enjoy or will help them to create and manage their monitors more efficiently;
  * To monitor and analyze trends and better understand how users interact with our Services, which helps us improve our Services and make them easier to use;
  * To measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition–for example, we may analyze how many individuals purchased a plan after receiving a marketing message or the features used by those who continue to use our Services after a certain length of time;
  * To monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, protect the security of our Services, detect and prevent fraudulent transactions and other illegal activities, fight spam, and protect the rights and property of Uptime Robot and others, which may result in us declining a transaction or the use of our Services;
  * To communicate with you, for example through an email, about offers and promotions offered by Uptime Robot and others we think will be of interest to you, solicit your feedback, or keep you up to date on Uptime Robot and our products; and
  * To personalize your experience using our Services, provide content recommendations, target our marketing messages to groups of our users (for example, those who have a particular plan with us or have been our user for a certain length of time), and serve relevant advertisements.

#### _**Legal Bases for Collecting and Using Information**_

A note here for those in the European Union about our legal grounds for processing information about you under EU data protection laws, which is that our use of your information is based on the grounds that:

(1) The use is necessary in order to fulfill our commitments to you under our Terms of Service or other agreements with you or is necessary to administer your account–for example, in order to enable access to our website on your device or charge you for a paid plan; or

(2) The use is necessary for compliance with a legal obligation; or

(3) The use is necessary in order to protect your vital interests or those of another person; or

(4) We have a legitimate interest in using your information–for example, to provide and update our Services, to improve our Services so that we can offer you an even better user experience, to safeguard our Services, to communicate with you, to measure, gauge, and improve the effectiveness of our advertising, and better understand user retention and attrition, to monitor and prevent any problems with our Services, and to personalize your experience; or

(5) You have given us your consent–for example before we place certain cookies on your device and access and analyze them later on.

## Sharing Information

#### _**How We Share Information**_

We do not sell our users’ private personal information.

We share information about you in the limited circumstances spelled out below and with appropriate safeguards on your privacy:

  * **Subsidiaries, Employees, and Independent Contractors:** We may disclose information about you to our subsidiaries, our employees, and individuals who are our independent contractors that need to know the information in order to help us provide our Services or to process the information on our behalf. We require our subsidiaries, employees, and independent contractors to follow this Privacy Policy for personal information that we share with them.
  * **Third Party Vendors:** We may share information about you with third party vendors who need to know information about you in order to provide their services to us, or to provide their services to you. This group includes vendors that help us provide our Services to you (like payment providers that process your credit and debit card information, fraud prevention services that allow us to analyze fraudulent payment transactions, SMS and email delivery services that help us stay in touch with you), those that assist us with our marketing efforts (e.g. by providing tools for identifying a specific marketing target group or improving our marketing campaigns), those that help us understand and enhance our Services (like analytics providers) who may need information about you in order to, for example, provide technical or other support services to you. We require vendors to agree to privacy commitments in order to share information with them. These vendors are listed in the "List of data sub-processors" section below.
  * **Legal Requests:** We may disclose information about you in response to a subpoena, court order, or other governmental request.
  * **To Protect Rights, Property, and Others:** We may disclose information about you when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Uptime Robot, third parties, or the public at large. For example, if we have a good faith belief that there is an imminent danger of death or serious physical injury, we may disclose information related to the emergency without delay.
  * **Business Transfers:** In connection with any merger, sale of company assets, or acquisition of all or a portion of our business by another company, or in the unlikely event that Uptime Robot goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would likely be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. If any of these events were to happen, this Privacy Policy would continue to apply to your information and the party receiving your information may continue to use your information, but only consistent with this Privacy Policy.
  * **With Your Consent:** We may share and disclose information with your consent or at your direction. For example, we may share your information with third parties with which you authorize us to do so, such as the social media services that you connect to our site.
  * **Aggregated or De-Identified Information:** We may share information that has been aggregated or reasonably de-identified, so that the information could not reasonably be used to identify you. For instance, we may publish aggregate statistics about the use of our Services.

## Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorized access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so, such as monitoring our Services for potential vulnerabilities and attacks.

To enhance the security of your account, we encourage you to enable our advanced security settings, like Two Step Authentication.

## Choices

You have several choices available when it comes to information about you:

  * **Limit the Information that You Provide:** If you have an account with us, you can choose not to provide the optional account information, profile information, and transaction and billing information. Please keep in mind that if you do not provide this information, certain features of our Services–for example, paid ones, may not be accessible.
  * **Opt-Out of Electronic Communications:** You may opt out of receiving promotional messages from us. Just follow the instructions in those messages. If you opt out of promotional messages, we may still send you other messages, like those about your account, monitoring alerts and legal notices.
  * **Set Your Browser to Reject Cookies:** At this time, Uptime Robot does not respond to “do not track” signals across all of our Services. However, you can usually choose to set your browser to remove or reject browser cookies before using Uptime Robot’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Uptime Robot’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.
  * **Close Your Account:** While we’d be very sad to see you go, if you no longer want to use our Services :( :( :( :(, you can close your uptimerobot.com account. Please keep in mind that we may continue to retain your information after closing your account, as described in Information We Collect above–for example, when that information is reasonably needed to comply with (or demonstrate our compliance with) legal obligations such as law enforcement requests, or reasonably needed for our legitimate business interests.

## Your Rights

If you are located in certain countries, including those that fall under the scope of the European General Data Protection Regulation (AKA the “GDPR”), data protection laws give you rights with respect to your personal data, subject to any exemptions provided by the law, including the rights to:

  * Request access to your personal data;
  * Request correction or deletion of your personal data;
  * Object to our use and processing of your personal data;
  * Request that we limit our use and processing of your personal data; and
  * Request portability of your personal data.

You can usually access, correct, or delete your personal data using your account settings and tools that we offer, but if you aren’t able to do that, or you would like to contact us about one of the other rights, scroll down to How to Reach Us to, well, find out how to reach us.

EU individuals also have the right to make a complaint to a government supervisory authority.

## How to Reach Us

If you have a question about this Privacy Policy, or you would like to contact us about any of the rights mentioned in the Your Rights section above, please contact us.

## Other Things You Should Know (Keep Reading!)

#### _**Transferring Information**_

Because Uptime Robot’s Services are offered worldwide, the information about you that we process when you use the Services in the EU may be used, stored, and/or accessed by individuals operating outside the European Economic Area (EEA) who work for us, other members of our group of companies, or third party data processors. This is required for the purposes listed in the How and Why We Use Information section above. When providing information about you to entities outside the EEA, we will take appropriate measures to ensure that the recipient protects your personal information adequately in accordance with this Privacy Policy as required by applicable law.

#### _**Ads and Analytics Services Provided by Others**_

Other parties may also provide analytics services via our Services. These analytics providers may set tracking technologies (like cookies) to collect information about your use of our Services and across other websites and online services. These technologies allow these third parties to recognize your device to compile information about you or others who use your device. This information allows us and other companies to, among other things, analyze and track usage. Please note this Privacy Policy only covers the collection of information by Uptime Robot and does not cover the collection of information by any third party advertisers or analytics providers.

#### _**List of Sub-processors**_

Uptime Robot uses the following products/services (which are all GDPR compliant):

  * **Limestone Networks:** for sending monitoring requests and storing data.
  * **Amazon Web Services:** for sending monitoring requests and storing data.
  * **Digital Ocean:** for sending monitoring requests and storing data.
  * **Nexmo:** for sending SMS and voice notifications.
  * **2Checkout:** for credit card payments.
  * **PayPal:** for PayPal and credit card payments.
  * **Google Analytics:** for analyzing the browsing behavior of our users and visitors.
  * **Google Ads:** for auto-pausing Google ads during downtimes.
  * **Facebook Ads:** for auto-pausing Facebook ads during downtimes.

## Privacy Policy Changes

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Uptime Robot may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Uptime Robot's sole discretion. Uptime Robot encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy.

**Change log:**

  * _July 15, 2019:_ Added Google Ads and Facebook Ads to the list of sub-processors.
  * _May 21, 2018:_ Updated for GDPR compliance.
  * _June 12, 2017:_ Removed Paylane from the list of payment processors.
  * _July 1, 2016:_ Updated the company name to reflect the change.
  * _May 20, 2014:_ Updated various typos.
  * _Nov 14, 2014:_ Added "payment processors used".

This "Privacy Policy" is based on the "Creative Commons" licensed policy by [WordPress](http://wordpress.com/) (the awesome guys that created WordPress).
